♪ 我的站到了 ♪
♪ This is my stop ♪
♪ 得下车了 ♪
♪ Got to get off ♪
♪ 还敢更挤嘛 ♪
♪ I might go pop ♪
借过
Excuse me
♪ 原谅我这么直 ♪
♪ I've got to be direct ♪
♪ 如冒犯请指教 ♪
♪ If I'm off, please correct ♪
♪ 你挡着我道了 ♪
♪ You're standing on my neck ♪
拽妹Daria
漫迪字幕组&@Daria拽妹黛薇儿
——·@严肃活泼小kk译制·——
好了 我把作文发回给大家
Now, as I'm handing back your essays,
你们可能会对...
you may have strong feelings
差异悬殊又让人沮丧的评分标准产生强烈不满
about the competitive and discouraging aspects of grading.
我很重视大家的意见
I care about what you have to say.
谁先说?
Who would like to start?
F+和D-是一样的吗?
Is an F+ the same as a D-?
我怕是从来没听过什么F+ Jordan
I don't believe I've ever heard of an F+, Jordan,
- 不过我们可以稍作讨论 - 她就说
- but we can talk about it. - So she said,
"我买了你说的乳白色紧身裤"
"I got those eggshell leggings like you told me,"
我应她 "乳白色? 我都说了是深紫色啦"
and I said, "Eggshell? I told you eggplant!"
搞笑的吧
You're kidding!
Quinn? 你有话要说么?
Quinn? Was there something you wanted to say?
我没有拿到作文
Um, I didn't get my essay back.
是没发给你 Quinn 恐怕下课后你得留下来
That's true, Quinn. I'm afraid I need to see you after class.
我会在镜子前给你留个位置哒
I'll save you a place at the mirror.
Quinn 我很抱歉 但我们得谈谈你的表现
Quinn, I'm so sorry, but we need to talk about your performance.
好吧 可我今天有点忙
Okay, but I'm kinda in a rush today.
来说回我们的期末任务吧
Let's go over our last assignment,
《我对文化多样性的看法》
"How I feel about polyculturalism."
你写的是"我相当喜欢全棉制品"
You wrote, "I definitely prefer all-cotton."
如果你是指抄袭的话 我可没有
I didn't copy it, if that's what you mean.
不 不 我相信你 问题是...
No, no, I believe you. The thing is...
我现在不想让你惶恐或心烦
now I don't want to panic or upset you
请务必带着建设性的目光来看待这事
please, take this in a constructive spirit
但恐怕你的语言艺术学得不咋地
but I'm afraid you're not doing well in Language Arts.
好吧 明天见
Okay. See you tomorrow!
我觉得你没理解我的意思
I don't think you understand!
你要在下一篇作文里拿到A
You're going to have to get an A on your next essay
才能保持及格
to maintain a passing grade!
你是说"及格或挂科"的那个及格?
You mean, passing as in "passing or failing"?
是 可别担心
Yes! But don't worry.
你要做的就是痛下保证 尽心尽力 和认真刻苦
All it will take is some commitment, dedication, and hard work!
噢 别啦
Oh, no!
你能做到的 Quinn
You can do it, Quinn!
你知道吗 我上高中那会儿呀
You know, when I was in high school,
我卯足干劲只为在体操队谋得一席之位
I wanted more than anything to be on the gymnastic team,
可我就是搞不定高杠
but I just couldn't master the high bar.
所以我每天训练...
So I practiced every day...
随即考验来临 你成功入队了
And the big tryout came and you made the team.
噢 不是
Well, no.
不过就在那个冬天
But that winter,
我学会了如何用牙咬着铅笔写字
I learned how to write while holding a pencil in my teeth.
Quinn 你知道这意味着什么吗?
Quinn? What is the meaning of this?
我辛苦工作了半天
I put in another twelve-hour day
结果回家看到的第一件事是...
and the first thing I see when I get home...
Jake
Jake!
- 我醒啦 - 孩子们哪去了?
- Ah! I'm up! - Where are the girls?
刚还在这呢... 我想是吧
They were here before... I think.
这让我非常不满
I'm very upset about this.
好吧 我知道啦
Oh, yeah, I know!
瞧 我刚想打电话点播电影呢
See, I was trying to call the number for Movie Phone,
结果这女人就莫名其妙地接了...
and out of nowhere this woman comes on the line...
Jake 你在说什么呀?
Jake, what are you talking about?
那不是电话账单么... 我... 那是什么?
That's not the phone bill. I... what is that?
是Quinn的老师写的信
It's a letter from Quinn's teacher.
她的英语要挂了 因为她没付出任何努力
She's going to fail English because she's not putting in any effort.
我要去楼上找她谈谈
I'm going up to go talk to her.
等一下
Wait a minute.
凭什么就不能是我来和孩子们谈?
Why can't I ever be the one to talk to the girls?
亲爱的 不是说你不能啦
Honey, it's not that you can't.
就是... 一个严格的家教团队好比一个合唱团嘛
It's just... a strong parenting team is like a singing group.
主唱负责领唱
The lead singer carries the tune,
伴唱的负责给她合音
and the backup singers support her.
那就是你啦
That's you!
那伴唱们都要做些什么?
But what do the backup singers do?
你在恰当的时刻帮腔
You chime in at just the right moment
然后就保持沉默 这样一说不是很恰当嘛?
and then you fade into the background. Doesn't that make sense?
我要拿个铃鼓什么的吗?
Do I get a tambourine or something?
老妈 我能借...
Mom, can I borrow...
我只是想去动物收留所
I'm just going to go run down to the animal shelter
看有没志愿者的差事啦
and see about volunteering.
我听说他们刚收留了一群病鸟
I heard they got in a new bunch of sick birds.
Quinn 这是学校寄来的
Quinn, this note came from school.
担心啥哟
Don't worry.
我要做的就是在下一篇作文里拿到A
All I have to do is get, like, an A on my next essay
然后就没问题啦
and I'm fine.
对这事我押上拉斯维加斯的赌注赔率
I'll take the Vegas odds on that one.
Daria 我们得鼓舞士气
Daria, we need to be encouraging.
坐下 Quinn 亲爱的 这不仅仅是一篇文章的问题
Sit down, Quinn. Honey, this isn't just about one essay.
是要你制定人生目标并实现
It's about setting goals in life and going after them.
你知道吗 我上高中那会儿呀
You know, when I was in high school,
我卯足干劲只为在游泳队谋得一席之位
I wanted more than anything to join the swim team...
别 别 求你别再说了
No! No! Please, not again.
老妈 你继续"想当年"的话
Mom, if you're going to reminisce,
恐怕会逼我去求助社会服务署
I'm afraid I'll be forced to call Social Services.
好吧 Quinn 我换种方式说
All right, Quinn. Let me try to put it another way.
在生活中不管你决定要做什么 良好的教育都...
No matter what you decide to do in life, a solid education...
你说过这话啦 就是我被抓到逃...
You gave this talk when I got caught cutting my...
是我忘了数学课在哪上的那次
when I forgot where my math class was.
Helen 让我来
Helen, let me.
亲爱的 你有没有听过蚂蚁和蚱蜢的故事?
Honey, did you ever here the tale of the ant and the grasshopper?
真恶心 虫耶?!
Ewwww! Bugs?!!
试着这样想 Quinn...
Try imagining it this way, Quinn...
你可能会留级
You could be left back
并变成朗岱尔高中最大龄的新生
and be the oldest freshman at Lawndale High.
你猜咋地? 我要去学习了 拜
You know what? I gotta get to work. Bye!
真是我的乖女
That's my girl!
瞧见了吧?
You see how it's done?
Daria 你在屋里吗?
Daria, are you in there?
不在 我在塔希提岛放松几天呢
No, I'm taking it easy in Tahiti for a few days.
等会哟 我要续一杯椰子得其利鸡尾酒呢
Hang on, I'm just ordering another tray of coconut daiquiris.
我在想能不能...
Um, I was wondering if...
不能
I don't think so.
人家的作文需要一点帮助啦
I just need a little help with my essay.
就是 你能不能帮我写嘛?
Like, could you write it for me?
这次我又要本着什么动机?
And what's my motivation again?
拜托啦 Daria 我们是姐妹耶 我们得互相扶持
Come on, Daria, we're sisters! We gotta stick together.
你的意思是公共场合除外吧
Unless we're in public, you mean.
可你这么聪明 那作文又这么重要
But you're so smart, and this essay's so important.
相信我啦 我能写就写啦 可我有个约会
Believe me, I would do it myself, but I have a date.
噢 那可不一般
Oh, that's different.
报酬怎么算?
When does the subject of compensation come up?
十块?
Ten?
二十
Twenty.
十五块
Fifteen.
成交
Done.
谢啦 Daria 这对我俩都有好处
Thanks, Daria. This is going to work out for both of us.
我是说 我能搞定我的作文
I mean, I get my essay written,
你至少也能给周五的夜晚找点寄托
and for once you'll have something to do on a Friday night
不会像傻瓜似的无所事事 对吧?
instead of sitting around like a loser, you know?
够了 莎士比亚 你特么自个儿做吧你
That's it, Shakespeare. Do your own damn homework.
这是Quinn的家吗?
Um, is this Quinn's house?
是有一个叫Quinn的人住在这
Someone by that name does live here.
那就好
Cool!
她在楼上做作业呢
She's upstairs doing schoolwork.
我就该对我拿到的地址留个心眼儿
I gotta pay more attention when I get these addresses!
Corey 我是下来告诉你我今晚不能约会啦
Corey, I just came down to say I can't see you tonight.
我要写作文
I have to write an essay.
好借口 来嘛 我都为今晚制定好特殊计划啦
Good one! Come on, I've got a special evening planned.
走吧 趁汽车影院还没排长队前出发
Let's go! Before there's a line at the drive-in.
不 说真的 Corey 我得做作业 你得离开 对不起啦
No, really, Corey, I have work to do and you have to leave. Sorry!
Quinn 他们到底怎么你了
Quinn, what have they done to you!
你梳妆打扮了两小时
Did you just spend two hours dressing up
就为了在门口用一分钟放人家鸽子?
to go the door for one minute and dump your date?
Daria 如果你在最靓丽的时候拒绝一个男生
Daria, if you look your best when you blow a guy off,
他们就会觉得你是真的有在意
it makes them feel like you care.
好吧 这建议应该会很有用
Well, that advice should prove very helpful.
有时候你肤浅得如此透彻 几近深奥
Sometimes your shallowness is so thorough, it's almost like depth.
谢谢 算了 20就20吧
Thanks. All right, twenty.
不要
Nope.
好咯 希望你能意识到你在让我自力更生写作文
Fine! I hope you realize you're making me do my own homework!
这想法还真吓人
That is a scary thought.
我给大家带来了一个特别的惊喜哟
I have a special surprise everyone.
继上周的写作课后我们中有位同学大有进步
One of our students has so improved since last week's essay,
我想和大家分享一下她的作文
I'm going to share her work with the class.
我真很喜欢你的紧身裤
I really like your leggings.
嗯 不过我现在不知道要搭什么鞋子 绑带的么?
Yeah, but now I have a shoe thing. Strappies?
穿有防水台的果冻鞋
Platform jellies!
Quinn 你真聪明
Quinn, you're so smart!
我只有对重要之事才会如此聪明
Only about important stuff.
Quinn?
我没拿到作文
Um, I didn't get my paper back.
你的确没拿到 Quinn 因为我要大声朗读它
That's right Quinn, because I'm going to read it aloud!
别啦
Oh, no.
《学术监禁》作者Quinn Morgendorffer
"Academic Imprisonment," by Quinn Morgendorffer.
"那接着来呀 用作业和试题禁锢我
"So go ahead! Lock me up with your homework and your tests!
用阅读和思考夺走我的自由
Rob my freedom with your reading and your thinking!
就我看来
As far as I'm concerned,
学校和监狱的唯一区别就只有衣橱罢了
the only difference between school and prison is the wardrobe.
还是你想把我的衣服也夺走? 完毕"
Or do you want to take away my outfits, too? The End."
有没有人想做一下点评?
Wow. Would anyone like to share their reaction?
请问我能转学么?
May I please change schools?
好哒 现在就能全面展示啦
There. Now it's on full display.
像一扇成就之门
Quite the door of achievement.
来嘛 孩纸 你想鼓励你的妹妹吧?
Come on, kiddo. You want to encourage your sister, don't you?
在门上取得一席之位么 嗯
To get her own place, yeah.
嘿 这是我的天才女儿
Hey! It's my daughter the genius.
我们独一无二的尖子生
Our own academic achiever.
我们都太为你骄傲了 对吧 Daria?
We're all so proud of you. Aren't we, Daria?
嗯 如果你是指错愕的骄傲
Sure, if you mean proud as in "stunned."
妈咪 爸比 让你们欣慰是我想要求的最大奖励
Mom, Dad, making you happy is the greatest reward I can ask for.
当然啦 其他小孩取得好成绩时
Of course, when other kids get a good grade,
有时他们会得到一些小礼物呢
they sometimes get like a little present.
听着 Quinn 我真觉得...
Now, Quinn, I really think...
我来处理 你说得太对了 亲爱的
I'll handle this. You're absolutely right, sweetheart.
你拿到A 值得奖励 来 给你的
You get an A, you should be rewarded. Here ya go!
谢谢爸比
Thanks, Dad.
等下 这不是双重标准吗?
Wait. Isn't that a double standard?
她拿个A 你就给她二十块钱
You just gave her a twenty for getting one A.
我以前拿的A全是义务劳动?
What about all the As I get for free?
可这是特殊情况
Yeah, but this is a special occasion,
所以Quinn就特别对待啦
so Quinn gets a special reward!
这关乎励志
It's a motivational thing.
可那不会让你各方面都一贯表现良好的...
But won't that demotivate your other daughter,
另一个女儿消极么?
whose work is consistently good?
就是 Jake 你要拿这怎么办?
Yes, Jake, where are you going with this?
我还没处理完呢
I wasn't finished.
Daria 一贯表现良好
Daria should have a consistent reward
值得持续性的奖励
for her consistently good work.
Quinn 在一次性特例中就得给...
And Quinn should have a special one-time reward
一次性的特定奖励
for her one-time effort!
可长期保持表现良好
But what about a higher reward for maintaining
该得到更高的奖励吧?
a standard of excellence over time?
算复合利息吧?
Perhaps with compound interest?
行行行 都拿去
Here, just take it!
Helen 都和你说过我不擅长做教育工作啦
Helen, I told you I was no good at this parenting crap!
嘿 Quinn 你红啦
Hey, Quinn, you're famous!
哎呀 你们呀 我只是非常受欢迎而已啦
Oh, you guys. I'm just really popular.
他是说你的作文上《朗岱尔内幕报》啦
He's talking about your essay in the Lawndale Lowdown.
校报?!
The school paper?!
在《机灵想法》那栏
It's in the Smart Thoughts column.
我完了
I'm ruined.
《学术监禁》作者Quinn Morgendorffer
"Academic Imprisonment," by Quinn Morgendorffer.
这不是很赞么?
It's great, isn't it?
"阳光照不进这四面砖墙
"No light shines through these four brick walls.
因为学校是我的牢房 老师是我的监守人"
For the school is my prison, and its teachers my imprisoners."
我打赌你压根不知道有个词叫"监守人"吧
I'll bet you didn't even know that the word "imprisoners" existed.
嗯 不过我可迫不及待要学以致用啦
Yeah, but now I can't wait to use it.
这到底哪赞了?
Why exactly is this great?
因为现在Quinn要尝尝
Because now Quinn's going to see firsthand
做书呆子的滋味了
what is feels like to be a brain.
听听这话
Listen to this.
"像在那旋转笼子里跑着的仓鼠
"Like a hamster on one of those wheel things,
学校让我们旋转不息
school runs us around and around
直至我们生出对饲料的渴望
until we yearn for the little food pellet.
但等待我们的只有更多的作业"
But only more homework awaits."
你造吗 就好像她能读取我的心思呢
You know, it's like she read my mind.
恰好在你头部严重受创后
Right after you suffered a severe blow of the head.
你能把那报纸收起来么? 到处都是
Could you put that away? They're everywhere.
你在这干嘛? 你坐的那张桌有炸弹么?
What are you doing here? Bomb scare at your table?
小声点 行吗?
Keep it down, okay?
自从校报发行后 我就一直想保持低调
I'm trying to keep a low profile since the paper came out.
你真走运 普利策委员会刚吃饱饭
Lucky for you, the Pulitzer committee already finished eating.
美国普利策奖 分有新闻奖和文学艺术奖
他们吃了肉卷
They had the meatloaf.
你一定对别人怎么称呼你很激动吧
You must be very excited about what people are calling you.
怎么称呼?
What?
智者Morgendorffer
"Brains" Morgendorffer.
拜托 就因为一篇小作文?
Come on, because of one little essay?
这是下坡路 看呐 你的未来写照
It's a slippery slope. Behold, the future.
上周 他们去参加橄榄球甄选
Last week, they were trying out for football,
结果赢了一个辩论赛
then they won one debate tournament.
我要怎么办? 我不能做书呆子
What am I gonna do? I can't be a brain!
朋友们会讨厌我的
My friends will hate me!
是的 但只要你想想你会在棋艺社交到新朋友
Yes, but just think of all the new friends you'll make in Chess Club.
也许我该趁其他人还没读到校报
Maybe I can steal all the newspapers
就把它们全偷走
before anyone else reads them.
嘿 不对劲啊 智者
Hey, wait a minute, "Brains."
你这时段不应该是在吃饭吧?
You don't even have lunch this period, do you?
当然不是啦 我翘掉科学课来找你
Of course not! I cut Science to talk to you.
你觉得我年级的人都在饭堂 我会和你坐一桌嘛?
You think I'd sit with you while my grade is at lunch?
还是在讨论"做书呆子绝壁错误"?
About that being mistaken for a brain thing?
我可不怎么担心
I wouldn't worry too much about it.
你到底为什么要在自修室学习?
Why do you have to study during study hall, anyway?
Quinn在辅导我的英语
Quinn's tutoring me in English
这样我就能继续待在球队了 这是O'Neill老师的指令
so I can stay on the football team. Mr. O'Neill set it up.
Kevvy 我也能辅导你 我也讲英语呀
Kevvy, I could tutor you! I speak English too, you know.
宝贝 我想到一个主意了
Babe, I've got a plan.
你最好想到了 你 你个卡萨布兰卡小毛头
I'll bet you do, you, you high school Casablanca!
不 宝贝 我是为了我俩才这么做的
No, babe, I'm doing this for us.
我是要去观察聪明人的行为
I'm going to, like, observe the way a brain acts,
然后我们就能加以模仿并变酷啦
and then we could act that way and be cool, too.
Kevvy 你太聪明啦 你在我眼里早就是聪明人啦
Oh, Kevvy. You're so smart. You're already a brain in my eyes.
谢哟 宝贝
Thanks, babe.
只有Quinn才能把聪明变成时代的潮流
Only Quinn could turn being smart into a fad.
甭担心 今天流行聪明 明天穿个舌孔
Don't worry. Today it's brains, tomorrow pierced tongues,
接着后天给脑子也打个洞
then the next day, pierced brains.
嗯 反正这对她也没差
Well, it's not like it's going to get her anywhere.
所以O'Neill老师就说我可以免听剩下的课
So then Mr. O'Neill said I could skip the rest of his class
早点吃午饭
and go to lunch early
因为我领悟得太快了
because I was catching on so fast.
很厉害吧?
Isn't that great?
你想见我?
You asked to see me?
Daria 你知道我很崇拜你写的作文
Daria, you know I'm a big, big fan of your writing.
可最近 你写的东西有点儿 怎么说呢 平淡
But lately, it seems kinda of, I don't know, flat.
我期待你能写点更... 花哨的东西
I'm looking for something a little more... jazzy!
jazzy也译爵士乐
你想让我来段架子鼓独奏?
You want me to put in a drum solo?
我是想知道你对于一对一辅导的看法
I was wondering how you'd feel about some one-on-one tutoring.
有点像迷你写作研讨会
Sort of a mini writing workshop.
我想让你见一个人
There's somebody I want you to meet.
她应该随时会...
She should be here any ...
嗨 你想让我... 辅导谁吗?
Hi, you wanted me to... ...help somebody?
你们认识呀?
Do you two know each other?
我就该说 "我才不用学她的写作方式
I should have said, "I don't need tutoring to write like her.
和蜡笔画似的"
Just some big crayons."
真是糟糕
Tough day.
我才不会让这事影响我
I'm not letting it get to me.
嗯 我知道
Yeah, I can see that.
大家看呀 我在吃薯条的时候又写了另外一首诗
Look everyone! I wrote another poem while I was eating my fries.
到我来朗读了
My turn to read!
"油乎乎的薯条 它不会撒谎
"The greasy fry, it cannot lie.
真相就写在你的大腿上"
Its truth is written on your thighs."
哇 Quinn 真是超赞的耶
Wow. Quinn. That's amazing.
文风优美
Beautiful.
天才
Genius.
我就说嘛
I know!
且慢 我觉得我要文思泉涌了
Hold it. I think I feel a poem coming on.
不好意思 虚惊一场
Sorry, false alarm.
嗯 我可能会从事写作这行
Yeah, I might do writing for a career.
这不算什么真正的工作
It's not like real work or anything.
真的 我是说 打字有什么难的嘛?
Really. I mean, how hard it is to type stuff?
还有很多机会呢
And there are lots of opportunities.
你造他们会在贺卡里加入诗歌吧?
Like, did you know they pay money
for those poems inside greeting cards?
噢不 我一直都无偿替他们写诗啊
Oh no! I've been giving my poems away for free!
能帮我一个忙么?
Do me a favor, will you?
嗯?
Yeah?
关上柜门
Close my locker.
哑剧大师爬进来死在这了?
Did a mime crawl in here and die?
我在搭配衣服啦
I'm putting together an outfit.
供你参考一下 人们就是这么注重着装
For your information, this is how deep people dress.
嗯 十分注重做作的人
Yeah, deeply affected people.
西方存在主义哲学流派
以人为中心 尊重人的个性和自由
谢谢 对了 你知道存在主义是什么意思吗?
Thank you. By the way, do you know what existential means?
因为今天有人说我的作文很存在主义
Because today someone told me my writing was existential,
所以我想我要调整一下 用衣服来调整
so I thought I should coordinate, you know, with wardrobe.
对 那就是加缪会做的事
Yeah, that's what Camus would have done.
存在主义文学领军人物 荒诞哲学的代表
根据你的情况 存在主义是指
For your purposes, existential means
"穿戴着街市里买来的配件的伪知识分子"
"pseudo-intellectual poser with accessories from the street fair."
听着 要是你想让我辅导你的作文 我会帮你的
Listen, I'm still available if you want help with your writing.
这黑色和项链配不配?
Does this black match?
和我的心情配
Matches my mood.
叛变的外科医生会趁你睡着移植你的大脑吗?
Can renegade surgeons transplant your brain while you sleep?
接下来为您播出《呕心小世界: 可怕的真相》
The frightening truth, next on Sick, Sad World.
你是不是有心事 Daria?
Is something bothering you, Daria?
没有
No.
你知道吗 和老爸谈谈心也未尝不可
You know, it's all right to have a heart to heart with Dad.
我也是做过不少家长工作的嘛
I've been known to do a little parenting in my time.
没关系的
It's okay.
你在想什么? 我来解决
What's on your mind? I'm up on the issues.
毒品 同辈压力... 还是帮派出事了?
Drugs, peer pressure... or is it a problem with your gang?
说是我个人问题比较恰当
It's more of a personal issue.
不是什么... 保健问题吧
It's not... hygiene or anything...
老爸 就假设你有一个你不怎么喜欢的身份
Dad, let's say you have an identity that you didn't even like...
好哇 比如有天醒来发现自己人到中年
Oh, sure! Like, one day you wake up middle aged
憎恨得很想逃离
and resenting the hell out of it.
好吧
Um, okay.
但是尽管你不喜欢这种身份
But even though you don't like this identity,
有人突然就抢了你的风头
somebody suddenly comes along and steals it from you.
你对此很沮丧 你本来就得到那种身份了
And you're upset. You earned that resentment,
那已是你的权利了嘛
it's your right.
嗯 更像是 你的确不想要这种身份
Well, it's more like, you didn't want this identity,
可有人把它抢走的话 你就什么都没有了
but if they take it away, you've got nothing.
要怎么办呢?
What do you do?
他们抢走你的身份了吗 Daria? 那你就一走了之
They took your identity, Daria? Then you walk away.
改头换姓 搬去别的州 弄张身份证
You change your name, move to another state, get some ID.
重新开始永远都不迟 Daria 永远都不迟
It's not too late to start over, Daria, it's not too late!
你还年轻
You're still a young man!
你不用背负错误过活
You don't have to live with your mistakes!
要适时离开
Get out while you can!
你该不会要摇我肩膀吧?
Um, you're not going to shake me, are you?
我要说的是
What I meant was,
坚持下去 那一切都会好起来的
you hang in there and everything's going to work out
老爸 和你聊完 我感觉好多了
Dad, talking to you has made me feel better about myself.
这是应该的 孩纸
That's what I'm here for, kiddo.
伴唱人员 哈
Backup singer. Ha!
我刚发现诗歌用不着押韵耶
Yeah, I just found out poems don't even have to rhyme.
多简单呀?
How easy is that?
出事了 Quinn 我们得谈一谈
There's a problem, Quinn. We need to talk.
出什么事了?
What problem?
好像其他女生都在效仿你的怪异行径
It seems that other girls are following your weirdo example
放弃时尚行头 穿得一身黑
and abandoning their fashion statements to wear all black.
一身黑也是时尚行头
Dressing in black is a fashion statement.
它有深度 有意义 还显瘦
It's deep, it's meaningful, and it's slenderizing.
杂志才不是这样说的
Not according to this.
大家都知道深紫色才是当前流行的暗色
Everyone knows that eggplant is the current neutral.
艾玛 我也阻止不了自己在这有影响力呀
Well, I can't help it if I have influence around here.
人们尊敬我的智慧
People admire me for my brains.
那可不是时尚俱乐部的教条
That's not how the Fashion Club works.
现在下令你正式放假 一直放到...
You're officially ordered to take a fashion sabbatical
你搞清楚事情的轻重为止
until you get your priorities straight.
我很担心Quinn
I'm concerned about Quinn.
我们得找她亲近的人
We need someone close to her
来让她意识到自己行为不当
to make her see the error of her ways.
可要找谁?
But who?
我有个计划 我们去和她认识的那女生聊聊
I had a plan. We'll talk to that girl she knows.
你真聪明 Sandi
You're so smart, Sandi!
而且你们还会发现我对此从不炫耀
And you'll notice I don't make, like, a big thing about it.
可那个女生很诡异
But that girl is so weird.
她吓坏我了
She freaks me out.
这就为什么我能当时尚俱乐部的主席了
That's why I'm president of the Fashion Club.
我来搞定她
I'll handle her.
你觉得那是要干嘛?
What do you think that was about?
我觉得我们永远都猜不透
I supposed we'll never know.
Jane 看仔细点
Jane, look carefully.
我有长出另外一个头么?
Have I grown another head?
没有 就两个
No, just the two.
再会
See ya.
她怎么了?
What's wrong with her?
没怎么
Nothing.
有没有要脑力帮忙解决的事?
Anything a little brain power could fix?
我猜她自己能搞定
I think she's had about her fill of that.
能问你个问题吗?
Can I ask you something?
什么?
I guess. What?
你不觉得我是书呆子吧?
You don't think I'm a brain, do you?
我从来没这样觉得过
The thought never crossed my mind.
我也没有
Mine, either.
我说 我很享受这样能打击到Daria
I mean, I really like the way this getting to Daria,
可我开始感到我是冒牌货了
but I'm starting to feel like a phoney.
你开始感觉自己是冒牌货?
You're starting to feel like a phoney?
我不就写了篇傻不拉几的作文嘛
So I wrote a stupid essay!
大家干嘛要这么在意?
What's everyone making such a big deal about?
你懂的 人们对什么事都不抱期待的话
Well, you know, condition people to expect nothing
那屁大点事都能让他们嗨起来
and the least little something gets them all excited.
问巴普洛夫去
Ask Pavlov.
苏联生理学家和实验心理学家 提出"条件反射论"
高级神经活动生理学的奠基人
管理员?
The custodian?
随便了 话不投机半句多
Never mind. Return to your world, and I'll return to mine.
对了 什么事在蚕食你的灵魂嘛?
By the way, anything eating away at your soul?
她的作文很烂
Her writing's bad.
难道人们连好和坏都分辨不清了么?
Don't people know the difference between good and bad?
她漂亮 长得好看的人适用于不同的标准
She's cute. There's different standards for cute people.
你说的是没有标准吧
You mean, no standards.
对
Right.
不是曾经有过不以貌取人的岁月么?
Isn't there ever a time when how you look
doesn't affect how you're judged?
除非是在你把眼睛作为捐献器官的岁月
When you donate an organ, unless it's your eyes.
听着 这没什么大不了的
Listen, it's no big deal.
重点在于 如果她是书呆子 那我是什么啊?
The thing is, if she's a brain, what do I get to be?
你还是书呆子
You're still a brain.
是 可她是有一头秀发的书呆子
Yeah, but she's a brain with bouncy hair.
我比不过
I can't compete.
好吧 那你就是... 超级书呆子
Okay, then you get to be... a super-brain.
比之前的更形影单只
An even bigger outcast than before.
我才胜任不了超级书呆子呢
I don't think I can survive being a super-brain.
到时她自然会停止了 不过要怎么才停?
Then she's got to be stopped. But how?
噢 我造了
Oh, I know how.
我只是没让自己这么做... 直到现在
I just haven't been able to bring myself to do it... until now.
嗯?
Yes?
等等
Wait.
不 搞错了 我们以为...
No, um, it's a mistake. We thought...
你眯眼眯够的话
If you squinted hard enough,
可能我会变成另外一款Morgendorffer?
maybe I'd look like a different Morgendorffer?
听着 你们真想要Quinn回归本性?
Look, do you really want Quinn back?
是
Yes.
绝对是
A thousand times yes.
让她回来
Bring her back!
你得让她回来
You gotta bring her back!
服从我的命令 我就交货
Do exactly what I say, and I'll deliver the goods.
嗨 能帮我拿瓶苏打么?
Hi! Could you get me a soda?
嘿 伙计 咋滴捏?
Hey, dudes! Whazzup?
Quinn 你约的人到啦
Quinn! Your dates are here!
其实我们是来约Daria的
Actually, we're here to ask Daria out.
就是你另外一个女儿啦
You know, your other daughter.
对了 Quinn怎么样啦?
By the way, how's Quinn?
闭嘴 Jamie
Shut up, Jamie!
嗨 Quinn
Hi, Quinn.
嗨 Daria
Hi, Daria.
艾玛 我要下去赴约了
Well, I'm off for my dates.
1... 2...
One... two...
等等 你赢了 行了吧?
Ugh! Wait! You win, all right?
是 我是没写作文
Yeah, I didn't even write the essay.
我在垃圾桶找到一篇就交上去了
I found it in the garbage and handed it in.
整件事就像失控的火车
The whole thing was, like, a runaway train.
好吧 不过还是解释不通黑衣黑裤的事
Well, that still doesn't explain black clothes,
不过我想这就算了
but I guess I can let it slide.
别担心 我受够做知识分子了
Don't worry, I'm through being an intellectual.
我太能适应环境
I'm too well-adjusted.
找脑子的茬 可是很危险的
Messing with the mind can be so dangerous.
说说看
Tell me about it.
我猜一切都恢复正常了
I guess things are back to normal.
时尚: 好 思考: 烂
Fashion: good. Thinking: bad.
我们赢喽
Yeah. We win.
我屹立于世界之巅
I'm on top of the world.
欢迎微博关注
@漫迪字幕组